Ven. Pomnyun's Journey
Toward Happiness and Freedom
Q: How did you become involved in
international relief activities, the
eco- movement and the peace movement?
Solving our problems
on our own is practice.
After becoming free of
suffering ourselves,
we can use our time and energy
to help others find happiness.
I believe it is not appropriate to ask
why a practitioner does such work
because a practitioner is supposed do them.
Such work can be considered
to be a natural part of practice.
While helping others become happy,
we need to address
the sources of their suffering.
If discrimination is the problem,
we need to find ways to end it.
If they are suffering from hunger,
we need provide them with food.
I try to participate in such
activities as much as I can.
In addition, I encourage and guide
others to join me in such efforts.
Q: Unlike other monks
who practice and give dharma talks
at Buddhist temples,
you reach out to people
in public places
with your dharma dialogues.
Is there any special reason for it?
“What is the ultimate goal of life?”
“How should I console my friend
who recently lost her parents?”
“How do you balance between
environment preservation and development?”
“Is there a past life?”
When I give dharma talks in public places,
anyone can attend
regardless of his or her religion.
Also, when people share
their problems with me,
we can have a dialogue in lay terms
and come up with a solution together.
That’s why I give my dharma talks in
public places and not just in temples.
Also, I believe practice means
being mindful at all times
so that we can always be happy,
lighthearted, and free.
Therefore, I can practice
while giving a dharma talk
or counselling people
about their concerns.
Practice is being mindful and observing
our minds while doing these things.
Thus, I believe we should not insist on
certain formality associated with practice.
Practitioners should make
themselves happy and free.
At the same time, they should also
help others attain happiness and freedom.
Then, it is good for both me and you,
and it is good for
both now and the future.
This is the teaching of the Buddha.
I practice and spread the teachings
of the Buddha based on this belief.
Regardless of topic,
let's engage in a dialogue.
It's good?
His journey to bring happiness and
freedom in people's lives continue today.
“Shall we begin our dialogue?”